由于全世界都已得悉的行动结果
Without any exception, known now by all the world,
1939年9月3日
it's now Sunday, September the 3rd, 1939,
成为人们长久铭记的日子
as a day to belong remember.
今天上午11点15分
At 11:15 this morning,
首相在唐宁街十号向全国发表演说
the primary minister speaking to the Nation from No.10, Dunning Street,
宣告英国与德国进入战争状态
announce the Great Britain is at the war with Germany.
同时殷切期望伦敦市民不要忘记已经发布的紧急状态令
Meanwhile, the London Public Earnest remind their emergency order already issued.
在灯火管制时间内不得露出任何灯光
No light at any description should be visible after black out time.
天黑以后任何人不得在街上游荡
No dogs or cats will be allowed to room at three through out of dark,
切记不得在公共防空洞里安置床铺
and the troops should've to remember the thief should not to be committed in public area shelter.
临睡前应将防毒面具和御寒衣服放在身边
Gas mask and warm clothing should be placed hence for retiring
建议在暖瓶里盛上热饮料
and he suggests the warm drinking of cinnamon
这对在深夜时不得不被叫醒的儿童们会有很大好处
would be a great of comfort to small children who might have been waken at unusual hour.
要尽力稳定那些仍然留在伦敦的儿童们的情绪
If there's ever the troops maid to require the nurse of those children who still remain in London despite of the evacuation
尽管至今深夜撤退行动仍在持续进行
which would continue the late hours until this evening.
克劳宁上校的车
Colonel Cronnie's car!
我说对了 汤马斯 就是今晚
I was right, Thomas. Tonight!
您要去法国
To france, Sir?
去滑铁卢车站
Waterloo Station!
是
Yes.
那儿你很熟悉吧
Be familiarity you wanted it.
我是说您经历了上次大战
I mean I've been to the last one.
是啊 是很熟悉
Yes, it would be familiar.
汤马斯
Thomas
什么
Sir
从滑铁卢桥去车站
Go by way of Waterloo Bridge, will you?
滑铁卢桥
Waterloo Bridge? Sir?
时间还够
We have plenty of time.
好的
All right, sir?
把车开到桥那头
Wait for me at the other end of the Bridge.
我走着过去
I'll walk across.
是的 上校
All right.
哦 这给你
Here, take this!
吉祥符
Good luck chuck?
也许它会给你带来运气
Perhaps it would bring you luck.
我想它会的
I hope it will.
我真希望它会
I prey it will.
哦 你真是太好了
It's such wonderfully kind of you
你现在不会忘记我了吧
Do you think you remember me now?
我想不会
I think so.
不会的
一辈子都不会忘记你
For the rest of my life.
听 空袭警报
I hear it.
你在做梦吧
Oh, you're dreaming.
我什么也没听见
I didn't hear a thing.
我听见了 你们听
Well, I didn't...Did you? Myra
又来了
And it rings again.
怎么办呢 你们安静点
Be quiet, please, all of you.
对不起 那是空袭警报吗
Pardonme, but was that a warning?
恐怕是 一会儿就知道了
I'm afraid so, we'll know in a minute.
空袭 你们还不信
Myra, I told you, we'll be late
夫人会发脾气的
Madame will be furious.
我们还替夫人担心呢
We shouldn't worry about Madame.
瞧 瞧啊
Look! Look!
它在哪儿呢
Where was he?
我们去哪儿好呢
Where can we go?
去地下铁道车站吧
The other front station on your right.
右边
On your right!
右边 嘿 右边
Your right! Your right!
我真傻 总是这样
Stupid bag, it always does this.
太谢谢你了
Thank you so much.
也许他们要扫射这桥
Mind your own life, we might be stretched.
快走吧
We'd better get off.
哦 我的吉祥符
Oh! My lucky chuck!
你不想活了
You're a fool, you'll out of life.
不能丢这儿
I have it years,
它带给我运气
it brings me luck.
带给你空袭
That is outrages.
要是我们跑的话 那就太不像军人了
Do you think there'll be troops on Miller Street if we could run.
没关系
Not at all.
嘿 别推我 先生
You idiot, don't push me, sir.
我就说幸亏推了你
And I say you blow me well push
要不是我们的几条腿 你还在门外面呢
if you later would like to staying outside.
我是一向靠自己跑
I was always right about myself.
我听上了年纪的人说 活动的靶子可不好打
That's my old man says a moving tart.It is others to eat.
是吗
Anti-?
当然
Not at all.
哎呀呀
Blinding!
特国人打得可准了
Urman's ready marks on March 18
特国
Urman?
是呀
Yes.
特国就是德国
Urman the German.
真对不起
I'm Sorry.
看来这股推劲还不小呢
It seems there is a certain amount of shaving.
很挤 是吗
It is crowd, isn't it?
这颗扔得很近
That one must close.
这儿安全
Ah, we're save here.
靠墙边好像人还少一点
There may be some space over the wall.
我们挤过去
Shall we make through?
好啊
All right.
对不起
Excuse us, please.
All right
好点吧
Better, yeah
是的 谢谢 好多了
Yes, thanks, much better.
找你的朋友
Look for your friends?
是的 也许她们从别的门进来了
Yes, perhaps they're taking another end.
不在意吧
Do you mind?
哦 不 不
Oh, no.
大概你不会吸烟吧
I suppose I must offer you one.
不 谢谢
Mm... no thanks.
你是个学生 是吗
You're on school, aren't you?
哦
Oh... ho...
这话可笑吗
I've being funny?
哦 瞧 我们的学校
Oh, look, that's our school,
基诺娃夫人的国际芭蕾舞团
Madam Olga Kirowa International Ballet.
国际芭蕾舞团
International ballet?
这么说你是个舞蹈演员啰
You don't mean to say you're a dancer.
是的
Yes.
是专业演员
Ah... professional dancer?
我看差不多吧
Now and then I wonder.
你是说你会转圈什么的
You mean you can very well nodor something
当然 我还会滑步呢
Certainly, I can do auto-sante
你说什么
I beg you pardon?
我能双脚腾空打击六次
I can cross my feet six times in mid-air
尤金斯基能做十次
It just could do ten
不过这一百年才出一个
but that only happen once in the Century.
哦 这对肌肉有好处
Must because of the muscle's of...
对肌肉有好处
Let's forget of the muscle.
舞蹈演员的肌肉就像男人的啰
I should think of the dancer's muscle be like strong man.
哦 那不见得 要这样的话 那真是太可怕了
Oh, not quietly, that'll be restrictful. We try to combine the slender and strength
我从十二岁开始就练舞蹈了
Well, I've been dancing since I was 12, and...
我一点都不觉得肌肉特别发达
I don't think the muscle is over-developed?
哦 不 不 你是例外
Oh... no, not in your case.
我们像运动员一样锻炼
Cause we have to train like gasoline
我们的生活有严格的纪律
Madame believes rigid discipline.
你今晚去剧场吗
You're expected to be in the theater tonight?
当然 十点才上场呢
We don't go on until ten.
但愿我能去看
Wish I could be there.
你来吗
Why don't you come?
可惜 上校那儿有个宴会
No, unfortunately I have Colonel's dinner.
我要不去那得有点胆子
Takes a lot of nerves to miss Colonel's dinner.
你是回来度假的
Are you home on leave?
快到期了
I haven't.
我家在苏格兰
My home is in Scotland
那你又得回去了 我是说去法国
And you have to go back to... to France... I mean?
明天
Tomorrow.
哦 太遗憾了
Oh, I'm so sorry.
可恶的战争
This hateful war.
是啊 我也这样想
Yes, I suppose it is.
这战争 怎么说呢
Yet, I don't know...
也有它的精彩之处
It owns certain amount of excitement too.
它能随时随地教人感到意外 引人入胜
On the corner every second fascination of the unknown.
就像我们这会儿这样的
We're both facing at the incident.
不 和平时期我们也会这样的
Oh, we're facing unknowing peacetime too.
你很实际 是不是
You're rather a matter of fact, don't you?
是的 你很浪漫 是不是
Yes, you're rather romantic, aren't you?
好了 空袭过去了
Well, here we are. Wait is over.
没经历过这么好的空袭吧
Never enjoyed in L. A more.
我们现在走还是等下一次空袭
Shall we go now or wait for the next.
这主意不错 我们还是走吧
Oh, very attempting, but... I think we'd better go
我帮你拿吧
Shall I carry that?
不 不
No, no!
我只有在紧急的时候才会掉的
I only drop it in the emergency.
啊 但愿下次掉的时候我在旁边
I hope I'm around next time it happens.
这不大可能吧
It isn't very like it, isn't it?
你要回法国
You go back to France.
你呢
And you...
我们可能去美国
We may go to America.
哦 这么说不可能罗
That does make it unlikely.
太遗憾了
I'm sorry.
我也是
So am I.
太晚了
Too late...
我得坐车走了
I'm afraid I'll have to take taxi.
车可不太好叫啊
Well, it may not be so simple.
知不知道 (要是我能)
I don't know your... (wish I could have seen... )
你想说什么
What you're gonna to say?
要是我能看到芭蕾
Wish I could go to see the Ballet.
在战壕里我就有愉快的回忆了
I'm sure it would be a pleasant memory in the trenches.
你想说什么
What were you going to say?
哦 可是我
Oh, it just... I...
前线的人我一个也不认识
I don't know anyone who's in France, and...
我是不会忘的
I'm afraid to bring it home
现在我认识了你 当然我并不完全了解你
Now I've known you, not I really know you of course.
谢谢 谢谢你了
Thank you very much.
我希望你能平安归来
I hope you'll get back save in town.
谢谢
Thank you.
哦 这给你
Here, take this.
这是你的吉祥符啊
Your... your good luck charm?
也许会给你带来运气
Perhaps it'll bring you luck.
会的
I hope it does.
我说我不能拿
Oh... I don't... I can't take it
这是你心爱的东西
It mean so much to you.
你拿着吧
You'd better to have it.
我已经过分依赖它了
I was beginning to rely on it too much.
哦 你可真太好了
Oh, that's wonderfully kind of you.
去奥林匹克剧场
Olympic Theater, please.
再会
Good bye.
基蒂 他来了
Kitty, he's here.
谁
Who?
在地下铁道的那位
The man you met on the ground?
我真不懂
I don't understand.
他说他不能来
He says he couldn't come.
可他还是来看演出了
Suppose he just come to see the show...
你说他要参加上校的宴会
You said he has Colonel's dinner?
这不是我说的 是他说的
It's not what I say, it's what he says.
他人不错 是吗
He's nice, isn't he?
人还不错
He's being all right.
可是他把上校给甩了
What did he do the corneal?
夫人会说话吗
Do you know what her man says?
我们得留神
Watching play?
姑娘们 姑娘们
Girls, girls!
姑娘们 哦 快点 快点
Girls, please, please to be quite!
夫人最恨乱吵吵了
You know how Madam hates noise.
莫琳 奥凡涅舞步怎么跳
Pauline, what is partabera?
奥凡涅舞步是仅次于小碎步的脚尖移动步伐
A partabera is progressional points by certain very small even steps.
既然知道 为什么演出的时候不这么跳
If you know it, why don't you do it during the performance?
艾尔莎
Elsa,
你那个迎风展翅毛毛糙糙的
your all abase-sware jumping, they were pussy timbly, elastic.
简直是疯疯颠颠
Really I was concern for you.
安娜
Anna
请你给这些年轻小姐
show the young lady, please?
跳一个腾空打击四次
How to do an encachgalta? I.
我想问一问 为什么你在观众面前不这么跳
And may I ask why didn't you do it that way for the audience?
他们有权利看真正的演出
They also have some rights, you know?
今天晚上的演出简直是丢脸
The performance tonight was disgraceful.
我们现在虽然是在游乐场演出 不过
We are playing for the moment in the Wallace Theater, but...
基蒂
Kitty?
不过这并不意味着你们就可以不用心了
But that doesn't mean you should work with less precision than
比你们前一个节目海豹的表演还差
performing sills, which proceed you.
你们不尊重芭蕾
You don't own the Ballet by your presssincere,
可芭蕾尊重你们
The ballet honors you.
有什么事吗
Are there questions?
什么 夫人
Madam?
纸条 基蒂
The note, Kitty?
纸条 刚才人家给你的
The note that was handed to you.
是个老朋友刚送来的
Oh, it is just from an old friend, and may I...
不用人说 我就知道你扮演了低级歌舞团里的一个配角
I don't need to be reminded that you were of course call girls in a review.
太不像话
Your behavior!
玛拉
Myra!
不 基蒂
No, Kitty!
这是给我的
It's for me, Madam.
那你念念吧
Then you may read it.
大声点
Aloud, please.
夫人 我
Madam... I...
请你念吧
Read it, please.
我终于觉得我怎么也不能去跟上校 度过我最后一个夜晚
As you see,I cannot bear just spend my last evening with my corneal after all,
请跟我一起吃晚饭
Please have supper with me,
防空壕的朋友
Your friend in the Shelter
我相信你会来的
P. S. I am sure you would because I have a good luck charm
因为吉祥符把我的运气转好了
which had already change my luck.
署名呢
And the signature?
没有署名
There isn't one.
如果要有的话
And if there were one.
是什么呢
What would it be?
不知道 我就知道他是个军官
I don't know, I only know his last name.Indeed!
好啊 我必须强调一下
I must emphasize.
如果你想要的是晚会啊 军官哪 快活呀
That if you want sub-parties, officers,
你就别呆在我这个地方
and at the last, you shouldn't be here with me,
去另找一个职业吧
but in other occupation.
莉迪娅 给我一张纸
Lydia, paper, please.
战争并不是随心所欲的借口
A word is no excuse for in the quarrel.
现在写吧
And write, please,
亲爱的先生
Dear sir,
什么军衔
What does he act?
上尉
Captain!
亲爱的上尉
Dear Captain,
给您的 先生
Here you are, sir.
啊 谢谢
Oh, thank you.
谢谢你 先生
Thank you, sir.
不行啦 先生
No goes, sir?
看来是不行了
No, I'm afraid not.
哦 上尉 你等等
Oh, captain, captain.
我是基蒂 玛拉的朋友
Captain, I'm kitty, Myra's friend.
你想在哪儿等她
Where do you like to meet her?
什么 玛拉
What? Myra?
哦 你好
Oh, how do you do?
哦 谢谢
I do very well, thank you.
你想在哪儿等她呢
But where do you want to meet her?
我
I...
可她 她拒绝了
But she... uh... she refuse...
哦 你别在意
Oh, take your note.
是夫人让她这么写的
There's an old drag made her to write that
那么说她来
You mean she'll come after all?
说吧 在哪儿等她
Name the place.
烛光俱乐部吧
Does she know the candle night's club?
好 我告诉她
No, but I do. Good, then...
一小时后 我在那儿等她
Then I'll be there, an hour, say?
那好吧
An hour.
我说
Look, here...
这件成人之美的差事我做得对不对
I... I hope I'm doing the right thing.
玛拉是个可爱的女孩
Myra's just a sweet child
你明白 是吗
You can see that, can't you?
我明白 基蒂
I can see that, Kitty.
再见 上尉
Bye-bye, captain.
你好
Hello
哦 我好
Oh! Hello
我正担心基蒂把地点说错了
I'm afraid that Kitty direct you to the wrong place.
没有
Oh no!
你的条子我当着大家的面念了
But I read the letter before the whole class.
你难为情吗
Were you embarrassed?
是的 你也会难为情
Yes, so would you, I believe?
我敢说
Mh... Idare say.
我使你为难了吧
I'm afraid I made it difficult for you?
啊 你 你把上校甩了
Well, you... you gave up the corneal,
所以 恐怕我也使你难为情了
so I spend a time very difficult to see you too.
是啊 可我得到了补偿
Yes sure you did, but I have my reward.
你来了太好了
It's wonderful to have you to come.
我们进去吧
Shall we go in?
好的
All right.
请原谅
Excuseme!
你真美啊
How nice you look!
谢谢
Thank you!
你们舞蹈演员吃什么
Mm... what a dancer eat?
舞蹈演员吃有营养的 脂肪少的
Oh, dancing... mostly netruous yet not fattening
哦 今晚例外
Oh, no... not tonight.
你这儿有什么特别的菜吗 我们要高脂肪 难消化
What do you suggest would be particularly rich and in adjustable?
龙虾不错 先生
The crab is very nice, sir
还有酒 不违反舞蹈演员的规矩吧
And wine, this begins against the rule,
稍微喝点淡酒
but dancer does drink a little light wine, isn't it?
对 不违反
Well, tonight?
好
Good!
来14号
No.14,please.
知道了 先生
No 14,sir.
啊 你的舞跳得很美
The ballet was beautiful!
我看不见得
Madame didn't think so.
内行不懂只有外行懂
Well, experts never know.
我跟你说 你跳得非常美
It takes outsider to know when I tell you it was beautiful.
这说明你确实是外行
That certainly proves you are an outsider.
再见到我高兴吗
You'd like to see me again.
是的
Yes.
我看你有点保留
I sense reservation.
说得对 是这样的
Well, I suppose there is one.
是什么
What?
为什么
Why?
这让我怎么说呢
What's the good of it?
你是个奇特的姑娘
You are a strange girl, aren't you?
我很想知道你是怎么想的
What's the good of everything? What's the good of living?
那也是个问题
That's a question, too.
哦 等等 我不想让你离开话题
Oh, no, wait a minute. I'm not let you get away with that.
生活里最美好的就是能发生这样的事
One of the thing about living is this sort of things can happen.
在空袭的死亡阴影里
The shadow of desperate,
能遇见你 我就充满活力
I can meet youa nd feel more intensely alive,
比和平时期悠闲的散步更有活力
and walking around in the peace time, taking my life for granted.
这代价太高了
It's high price to pay for it.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
我这么认为
I do.
难道人们非得互相残杀 才能给他们带来活力
Do people have to kill each other to give them a hiking sense of life?
可这和互相残杀完全是两回事
That's got nothing to do with people killing each other.
对生活不是充满信心
Are you excited about life or you're not?
就是麻木不仁 无动于衷
You know, I've never been able to wait for the future.
我还记得我很小的时候
When I was very young, a child in fact,
我像一个跳水员似的爬到一棵大树顶上
I climb to the top branch of a high tree to like a diver,
向女教师宣布 我要跳向未来
announce my horrify governance, now I shall take a leave into the future
而且真跳了
and I jump.
我住了两个月医院
I was in the hospital two months.
真该让未来慢一点
You should let the future catch up you more slowly.
哦 不 不 我天生这样 没办法
Oh, no, can't help it, I can't help it.
你看 要是我们在一般情况下相遇
OK., if we met in ordinary time with ordinary way,
那我们就只能谈谈上什么学校了
we're just about telling what school we went to.
可我们现在就不一样了
We're much further along, don't you think?
是吗
Are we?
你知道是的
You know we are.
我太高兴了 跳舞去吧
Oh! I'm too excited, let's dance?
好的
All right!
敬你
To you!
谢谢
Thank you!
敬我们
To us!
我还是不太明白
I still don't get enough quite.
什么
What?
你的脸
Your face.
那么年轻 那么美
It's all beauty, all beauty.
还有什么你不明白的
What is it you still don't get?
你知道我们分手以后
You know when I left you this afternoon.
我忘了你的长什么样了 记不得了
I couldn't remember what you look like, not for the life of me.
我想她美吗
I thought was she pretty?
丑吗
Was she ugly?
说实话 怎么也想不起来了
What was she like? I couldn't remember.
我非得赶到剧场看看你的模样
I simply had to go get back to the theater to see what does she look like?
现在不会忘了吧
And do you think you can remember me now?
我想不会 不会的
I think so. I think so.
一辈子都不会忘
For the rest of my life.
对我 你还想知道点什么
But what is it all about the muse you still don't get?
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
现在演奏今晚的最后一个舞曲
we now come to the last dance of the evening.
请你们跳一路平安
I hope you enjoy the farewell waltz.
待会儿跟你说 现在跳舞
I'll tell you later, let's dance now.
这些蜡烛什么意思
What does this mean of these candles?
你一会儿就知道了
You'll find out.
我给你写信
I'll write to you.
你回信吗
Will you answer?
当然
Of course.
迷人的夜晚 是吗
Wonderfully evening, wasn't it?
是的 谢谢你
Yes, thank you very much.
等我回来 我们 我们再去那儿
When I come back, we'll go there again.
好的
Yes.
那是我们的地方
There'll be our place.
是我们永远不能忘记的地方
That's where we're always re-catch this evening.
你看我们还会见面吗
You think we'll ever seen each other again?
我看很难说 你说呢
I think it's startful, don't you? .
是啊 我也这么想
Yes, I suppose it is.
你在饭店里想跟我说什么来着
What was that you started to tell me in the restaurant
你说你还不 了解我
you didn't understand about me?
现在用不着再说了
Mm..., no use to go into now.
跟我说说吧 我想知道
Please tell me, I would like to know.
我们一认识我就觉得这太神奇了
Well, it strikes me curious ever since I meet you,
就在这漫长的刹那间
you know, very early moment ages ago.
你是那么年轻 那么漂亮 又是那么悲观
That you're so young, so lovely, so defeat-ages...
我是说 你似乎对生活没什么指望
You don't seem to respect much from life?
也许你说得对
Well, is that right?
先是我们认识了 我喜欢你
For instance, I meet you, I like you.
现在我们又得分手了
And I assume so soon we'll apart,
也许我们再也不会见面了
perhaps we'll never see each other again.
你现在就想象得出
You can't conceive that then.
我们不会再见面了
I'll never see each other again.
是的 想象得出
Yes, I can't.
你住这儿
This where you live.
是的
Yes.
好 就这样了
Nothing to do about it, does it?
就这样 除了说再见
Nothing... except to say good bye.
是这样
I suppose so.
再见
Good bye.
再见 玛拉 亲爱的
Good bye, Myra, dear.
再见 罗伊
Good bye, Roy.
多保重
Keep well!
是的 你也多保重
Yes, you too, Keep well!
我不会怎么的
Mh... nothing can happen to me.
你的吉祥符守着我的
Your lucky charm will see you then.
它会的
I hope it will.
我真希望它会
I'll prey it will.
再见
Good bye!
是不是你先进去
Please leave me first.
好吧
All right.
我得修修这个扣了
Ah, I wish I can have this catch amended.
我早就跟你说了
What I've been telling you?
昨天它松开了两次
It broken open twice yesterday.
哦 基蒂 几点了
Oh! Kitty, What time is it?
现在差不多是十一点
It's... almost 11.
噢
Oh!
早上好 夫人
Good morning, Madame!
早晨好
Good morning!
我是来向你祝贺的 玛拉
I come to congraduate you, Myra.
祝贺什么 夫人
What? Madame.
你起床了
On-being up. Myra.
想想看你四点钟才回来睡觉 真不简单
Considering that you didn't go to bed until 4,it's remarkable.
我在想今天晚上你的演出
I have the feeling your performance tonight
会像得了梦游症的人一样
will give the effect of sleep walking.
不过她是第一次出去 夫人
That's the first time Myra's been out, Madam?
昨天晚上我让你写字条 给那位军官先生
When I made you to send the note to the Military gentleman.
是为了你 我是为了保护你
It was you I was trying to protect.
跟我在一起的姑娘我都喜欢
I'm fond of the girls who work for me
我不愿意她们去做随军妓女
I don't want them to be camp followers.
你要了解我就不会这么说了
You don't know him or you wouldn't say that.
我们就一点私生活不能有吗
Can't we have any private life at all?
当它有损于你们在剧院的生活 那就不行
Not when it cost your public clever theater.
我很庆幸的是 他没在这儿呆一个星期
I'm happy that he didn't stay here for a week.
否则的话 这一个星期的演出都得让他给毁了
Otherwise he would ruin six performances instead of one.
如果再出现这种事 不管是你还是别的什么人
If such thing should happened again with you or any of the others,
都必须马上予以开除
It means instant dismissal
今天晚上我们剧场再见 如果你没有什么不方便的话
I will see youat the theater tonight, if it is not too much trouble.
她这人怎么这么可恶
Oh... Why she's so curl and hateful.
这个老巫婆
Ah, the old booster...
她跟谁都这么说话
She talks always like that.
别往心里去
Never mind.
真扫兴
Spoil everything.
你别瞎扯了
Oh, rubbish!
你又累心又烦
You're upset and tired.
今天你就好好的休息一下
Why don't you go to bed?
没有排演
There's no rehearsal today.
不 我不累
No, I'm not tired.
过海峡碰上这种天气
Horrible morning for the Jamey Crossby.
他走了吗
I suppose he's gone now.
是啊 恐怕走了
Yeah, I suppose so.
基蒂 你看
Kitty, Kitty, Look!
他在这儿
He's there.
哦 天哪 他开小差了
Here is sergeant.
基蒂 他在这儿
Kitty, thanks God!
他没走 他在这儿
He's here!
他会上军事法庭的
He'll be called Marshall for this
哦 我得去 我得去
Oh, I gotta go, I gotta to!
别着急
Oh, calm down, will you?
他现在不会走开的
He would certainly understand it takes a while, Myra.
基蒂 你看见他了吗
Oh, Kitty, you speak to him too, don't you?
不要下去 叫他上来吧
Well, that certainly goes to bring him up.
哦 你站在窗口
Oh, get away to that window, you stupid thing...
哦 我怎么办 你这傻瓜
Your feet! You can't take it around and...
我的帽子呢
Where is my hat?
玛拉 看在基督的份上
Myra, for Christ's sake!
哦 基蒂
Oh... oh... Kitty
哦 要是 要是他
What if I... what if he...
你说呢
Oh! You suppose...
亲爱的
Oh! Dear...
哦 基蒂
Oh! Kitty...
你说呢
What do you think?
哦 基蒂
Oh, God, Kitty?
我这样行吗
Do I look all right?
是的 还可以 穿上衣服就更好
Yes, sure you look allright. You look better if you put your dress on.
哦 基蒂
Oh! Kitty...
过来
Ah, here...
穿上
Come on now.
快 快穿上 玛拉
Look, look... Myra...
你慢点
Stop it!
快点
Come on...
我该怎么办呢 他会走的
I don't know what I'm doing.
哦 天哪
I'm embarrassing...
哦 在哪
Oh! Dear!
帮我扣上
I hate those buttons.
基蒂 基蒂
Kitty, Kitty...
我正在想
I just want to...
基蒂 他回来了
Kitty, he came back.
我刚才还在想
It was the beginning to think.
他没走
But he didn't.
他回来了
He came back.
哦 他还在吗
Is he still there?
他还在
He is!
你等一等 等一等
Hey! Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
我去给你拿雨衣
I get you a rainypush...
你的雨伞在墙角
Between the ten and corner there.
来 穿上
Here, put this on.
哦 我走在前头
Now I'd better go fish.
千万别让夫人碰上了
You don't want to run into the man all the way down.
等等
Wait aminute.
警报解除
All cleared.
你可别发出什么假警报
Please tell him no more force long...
再这么折腾 我可受不了啦
I can't stand the excitement.
你好
Hello!
你来看我 太好了
Nice for you to come to see me.
别这么说
Not at all.
你没走
You... you didn't go?
海下有水雷
Couldn't...My orders has changed,
放假48小时
forty-eight hours to leave.
真是太好了
Isn't that wonderful.
是的 有整整两天
Yes, two whole days.
你知道 我一夜都在想你
I thought all about you last night.
睡也睡不着
Couldn't sleep for a wink.
你终于学会记住我了
You're merry to remember me last instance.
是的 刚刚学会
Yes, very merry.
玛拉 今天我们干什么
Myra, what do you think we're going todo this?
哦 我 我
Well... I... I...
现在不 由你这样
Oh, you want the time for that.
这样
What?
这样犹豫
For hesitate!
你不能再犹豫了
No more hesitating for you.
不能
No?
不
No!
那我该怎么样呢
What're the merry things you're going to say?
去跟我结婚
We're going to be marry.
哦 罗伊 你疯了吧
Roy, you must be mad!
疯狂是美好的感觉
Ah... no, it's marvelous sensation.
哦 罗伊
Oh! Roy!
理智点
Do be sensitive.
我才不呢
Not me!
可你还不了解我
But you don't know me!
会了解的
I discover you.
用我一生来了解
Spend the rest of whole my life doing it.
哦 罗伊 现在在打仗
Oh! Roy, it's war time.
因为你快要离开了
It's... it's because you are leaving so soon.
因为你觉得必须在两天内度过你整个一生
Because you feel you must spend whole of your life in forty-eighthours.
我们去结婚吧
We're going to be marry
除了你
It's you.
别的人我都不要
And it'll never be anyone else.
你怎么这么肯定
How can you tell that?
亲爱的
I must know it.
别吱吱唔唔了
None of your equlevent.
别再问了
None of your questioning.
别再犹豫了
None of your doubts.
就这样定了 知道吗
This is positive, you see.
这样肯定了 知道吗
This is firmarative, you see.
这样决定了 知道吗
This is final, you see.
我们去结婚吧
You are going to marry me.
知道吗
You see!
我知道
I see.
怎么回事 亲爱的
What's matter, darling?
我们去哪儿
Where are we going?
去宣布订婚
To uptown for engagement,
回兵营去
to theBaron, St. Thomas Square.
玛拉 我跟你说
Now, Myra, I want to give you a complete picture
目前会陷于什么样的麻烦
what I am going to let you in for.
好的
All right.
我要你知道一下某些情况
I have to going through certain back.
首先我亲爱的年轻小姐
In the first place, my dear young lady.
了解我是朗特谢步兵团的上尉
Am a captain in the rental ship Ulserlias.
挺唬人吧
Are you impressed?
挺唬人
Very much.
一个朗特谢步兵团的上尉 是不能草率结婚的
A captain in the rental ship Ulserlias cannot be marry casually.
要准备 要有很多手续和仪式
Requires men's preposition for melody... anything.
这我知道
I see.
这有点繁文缛节
It's alibraryritual...
是吗
Is it?
譬如一个朗特谢步兵团的上尉
For example, the captain in the rentalship Ulserlias
要结婚 必须得到他上校的同意
has before he marries to get concern of his corneal...
这很困难吗
Is that difficult?
也许困难 也许不
Well, it might or it might not be.
我看不那么容易
I think it's gonna be difficult.
这得看怎么恳求了
Great deal depends upon the potentationers.
看恳求的魅力 看他的热情和口才
On thecharmerof potentationers, on these others, on the eloquence.
玛拉 看着我
Myra, look at me.
是 上尉
Yes, captain!
怎么 你怀疑吗
Don't doubt how it comes
你太自信了 上尉
You're very competitive, captain!
你简直疯狂了 上尉
You'requite mad, captain!
你又莽撞 又固执 又
You're ragulartism, head strong and...
我爱你 上尉
I adore you.
你坐这儿
Now, sit here.
跟谁也别说话
Don't speak to strangers.
我一会就来
I'll be right back.
玛拉
Myra!
这么快
So soon?
不 我还没见着他呢
Oh, no, I've not see him.
有件重要的必不可少的东西我忘了
I've got something very important... In face, indispensable!
什么
What?
你的履历表
Your virus-certificate.
哦 我不知道放哪儿了
Well, I'm afraid I've been misled them.
我给你填上
I'll check them up.
那么
Now, then...
你在哪儿出生的
I assume you were born... where?
伯明翰
Berming.
年月
When?
1895年6月9日
July, 9, 1895
你父亲的职业
Father's occupation?
中学教员
Schoolmaster!
父母在吗
Parents living?
不
No.
我说
Ha... say, whatelse?
对了
Oh, yes!
你姓什么
What's your last name?
哦 罗伊
Oh, Roy!
莱斯特
Lester!
幸亏想到这个 这很要紧
Lucky I thought of that, that is very vital.
再见 莱斯特小姐
Good bye, Miss Lester!
再见
Good bye!
稍等一会儿
Wait just a second!
对不起
Excuseme, sir.
哦 什么事 克劳宁
Yes, yes, what is it, corneal?
能单独跟你谈谈吗
May I see you privately, sir?
我在吃饭呢
I am at lunch!
这事非常要紧
It's extremely important, sir.
昨天的宴会你让我们好等
You know Sanprous last night when he interrupted dinner.
现在你又想不让我吃饭了
Now you interrupt my lunch!
都是为了一件事情
It's all part of the same thing, sir.
哦 好吧 我就来
Ah, very well, back in a minute.
我非常抱歉
I am terribly sorry, sir.
不过我想你会理解的
But I think you understand.
但愿你能理解
I hope you understand.
你是不是能给我透露一点呢
You are not going me some sort of clue?
我很抱歉 昨天你的宴会我没能来
Sorry about interrupting your dinner last night.
不过你知道 上校
But... you see, corneal...
不管你想说些什么 你还是干脆说吧
Well, whatever it is, I hope you strictly it up
免得我消化不良
beforel get corny into the suggestion.
坐吧
Sit down.
我想我还是站着好 我急得不得了
Well, I'd rather stand if you don't mind, sir, I am inquite of hurry.
事情是 上校
The fact is, corneal...
事情 事情
...the fact... the fact...
究竟什么事情
What is the fact?
要是你允许
With your permission, sir.
要是你不反对
If you don't mind, sir.
今天下午我想结婚
I would like to get marry this afternoon.
哦 新娘是谁呢
And who is the bride to be, may I ask?
她叫玛拉莱斯特
Her name is Myra Lester.
我有她履历表
I have her virus certificate.
哦 你坐下
Sit down!
认识她很久了
Do you know her long.
可以说是久经考验
Long enough to be absolutely sure, sir.
她晋见过陛下吗
It's you being presented to the court.
我想她没有
Very much, sir.
可我想她是有资格去晋见的
But she is elect devoted for presentation with you.
克劳宁 你明天就要上前线了
Roy, you're leaving for the prompt tomorrow.
你这么匆匆忙忙的跟上前线有关系罗
You're sure that hasn't to do anything with your haste?
当然
Certainly, sir.
走之前跟她结婚
You see, I want to marry her before I leave.
那么她就可以跟我的母亲住在一起了
So that she can move to live with my mother until I get back.
我懂了
Mm... I see.
克劳宁 我看
We're approving this.
这件事事关重大
This is what your proto-responsibility.
我知道
I know, sir.
而且这个责任我本人也可能承担不了
And the responsibility that I cannot assure by myself.
我 我看你承担一下吧
I... wish you try, sir.
我补充一句 我不得不要求你去徵求
Sorry, but I'm afraid that I'll have to ask you to get the concern
名誉团长公爵的同意
with the grace colonelin chief.
明白了
I see.
他是你亲戚 他比我更能把这件事情处理好
As he is your relative, he can inquire more truthfully indeed, but I can't.
如果他同意了 也就是我同意了
However, to get his concern, you have mine.
谢谢你
Thank you, sir.
而且我希望你今后要办什么事 最好别选在吃饭的时间
And I hope your future engage will not take place during meal time.
我很抱歉
Sorry sir.
祝你幸运
Thank you, sir.
班德广场 瑞勒斯大厦
Reverent Steward Crowford, Sparrow Square!
是 先生
Yes.
克劳宁上尉来了
Captain Roy Cronnie...
啊 孩子 看见你很高兴
Oh, my boy, I'm glad to see you.
谢谢 叔叔
Thank you, sir.
的确很高兴 你好啊
Very glad to see you.
很好
Very well, sir.
什么时候走啊
When do you go back?
后天
Day after tomorrow.
希望你能活蹦乱跳的回来
You're beginning back for that to push camera, I expect.
我也这么希望
I hope so, sir.
坐下
Sit down.
谢谢
Thank you, sir.
假期过得好吗
Had a nice leave?
好极了
Wonderful!
好 好 应该如此
Good, good.
孩子 有什么事要我帮忙吗
During the service... well, my boy, anything I can do for you.
是的
Yes, sir.
什么事啊
What is it?
我 我想请你准许我结婚
I... I'd like you to concern my marriage.
你结婚
Marriage... ho... ho... ho...
这姑娘是谁
Who is the girl.
玛拉莱斯特小姐
Miss Myra Lester.
莱斯特 莱斯特
Lester... Lester...
萨里的
Salle?
不
No,
伯明翰
Birmingham.
伯明翰 莱斯特
Birmingham... Lester...
我认识她吗
Do I know them?
不 到时候你会认识的
No, but I can rambling that, sir.
你母亲认识她
Does your mother know her.
不 她会的
No, she will.
不过玛拉她父母死了 她一个人了
At least, Myra. Her parents are died, she lives alone.
哎呀呀 她是干什么的
Well, what does she do?
是舞蹈演员
She's a dancer.
舞蹈演员
A dancer?
是的
Yes!
她
She's...
她长得非常美
She's terribly nice, sir.
舞蹈演员
A dancer...
你知道 罗伊
You know, Roy...
我喜欢舞蹈演员
I like dancers.
哦 谢谢你
Oh, thank you, sir.
我是说这 这也难怪你
I mean... I... I don't blame you.
舞蹈演员
Dancers! Mm...
当然了 想当年
In my time, you understand?
是啊 想当年
Of course. AH...
我在你这个年龄也爱过一个舞蹈演员
When I was your age, I was in love with a dancer.
想跟她结婚
Wanted to marry her.
可她不愿意
She wouldn't!
啊 要是她愿意 就是你婶婶了
If she had accepted me, she would have been your ante.
那真会叫人高兴
Never have been delightful.
是啊 孩子 不瞒你说
Look here, my boy!
我对你的成绩很满意
No one telling I am very proud of your war record.
谢谢 叔叔
Thank you, sir.
那你知道自己做的事吧
Oh, you know what you're doing, I suppose.
是的
Yes.
你也会为她自豪的
You'll be proud of her, too, sir.
我肯定
I am sure.
我没必要相信什么所谓的门当户对
I don't necessary to believe what they called "Correct Marriage".
有不少这样的婚姻很不幸
See, many of them turn out to be badly.
好 我祝你好运 孩子
Wow, good luck, my boy.
祝福你
I bless you.
谢谢
Thank you, sir.
我会永远铭记在心
I'll never forget this.
她也会的
Neither will she.
这没什么
That's all right.
下次休假的时候带她来见见我
Bring her around this evening on your next leave.
会的
I shall.
好孩子
Byeing for then.
再次谢谢
Thank you again, sir.
舞蹈演员
A dancer?
我荣幸地宣布公爵已经同意
On the sustain,I have the honor to announce its greatest concern to
朗特谢步兵团上尉罗伊克劳宁
the marriage of captain Roy Cronnie at the Rental ShipUIserlias to
和伯明翰的莱斯特小姐的婚姻
Miss Myra Lester at Birmingham Worryorchard, England.
家庭不反对
No family opposition.
一点不
Not as expected.
没料到
Disappointed?
是啊 我有点怕
Too easy, I'm frighten.
真是悲观派的
Ha... defeated.
上哪儿 先生
Where to, sir?
到邦德街
Ah... Bond street.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
邦德街
Bond street?
到那儿去买戒指
Bond street for a ring.
普通的戒指
Very simple ring.
我不想宠坏了你
I don't want to spoil your straight at all.
然后到花店
Then to the florist.
你该有束花
You deserve a rosy.
再到圣马修教堂
Then to the St. Matthew's church.
去圣马修教堂
St. Matthew's?
真的
Really?
当然去圣马修了
Of course, St. Matthew's.
那儿对军人的婚姻可以办得快一点
They have proper tradition with rigid mental marriages,
进去的时候我们陌生 出来我们就亲密了
where walk-in many strangers and walk out couple friends...
你们从那个门进去
The door beyond is the chest, sir.
牧师在和唱诗班练习
You'll find the big choir at practice.
谢谢
Thank you.
好 亲爱的
Well, darling.
哦 罗伊
Oh, Roy!
终于到了
Shall we face?
事情来得太快了
It's been so quick...
你真的拿定主意了
Are you quite, quite sure?
玛拉 我这个主意是拿定了
Myra, I was never so sure anything in my life.
上一次你一走
In the moment you left me after the air ray.
我就感到必须马上再找到你
I knew I must find you again, quickly.
我找到了 就永远不让你走
I found you, I'll never let you go.
这一下放心了
Does that answer you?
你在这儿等一下
Wait here.
这是莱斯特小姐
This is Miss Lester.
你好 莱斯特小姐
How do you do, Miss Lester.
你好
How do you do.
真抱歉使你失望了 莱斯特小姐
I am sorry to disappoint you, Miss Lester.
现在我不能为你们举行婚礼
But I'm afraid that it's impossible for me to marry you now.
你们应该知道 根据法律
Do don't you forget that according to the law,
下午三点之后不能举行婚礼
no marriage can take place after three o'clock.
我已经跟牧师说过了 玛拉
I explain to the Deacon, Myra.
这是一个非常事件
That the this is the emergency,
我们想战争时期能通融一点
we thought during war time, something could bemanaged...
是不是可以帮一下忙
Isn't there really anything you could do, sir?
我们将万分感激
We'll pay our most grateful.
我很愿意帮忙
I'd like to help you.
不幸的是 这是法
But unfortunately, that is law.
但是如果你们明天十一点钟来这儿
However, if you would come tomorrow morning at 11 time,
我将十分高兴的为你们举行婚礼
I shall be most happy to purfome the ceremony for you.
可我们时间不多了
But we have so little of time.
哦 这只差几小时
Well, there are only few hours.
只不过我们的订婚要拖长一天了
I just means we'll have to be engaged for a whole day.
我不赞成订婚拖得太长 你说呢 牧师
I don't believe long engagement, do you, Deacon?
哦 除非双方年龄较大
Oh, not when the party are elder.
照你们的情况我想 到没有什么妨碍
But I think in your case, it can do no harm.
那么我明天十一点钟等你们
Then I should expect you tomorrow at eleven.
我们会来的
We'll be here.
钟打11下我们准到
11 precisely.
我也准时等候
We'll stroke the hours.
谢谢
I should be thank you.
谢谢你了
Good bye, thank you very much.
再见 莱斯特小姐
Good bye, MissLester.
再见 牧师
Good bye, deacon.
玛拉到底上哪儿了
Where's Myra, anyhow?
快八点了 得上剧场了
No more date, we've got to go to the theater.
我真为这姑娘提着心
I'll tell, I just tremble for the poor girl.
哦 你干嘛老是提着心
Oh, chorally, who's trembling?
也许她直接上剧场去了
Maybe she went to the theater
说对了
That's right!
可能她等着我们呢
She's probably waiting us there.
但愿如此
I hope...
哦 你上哪儿去了
Where have you being?
真把我愁死了
I've been worrying to death.
我以为你们在一起 可他打来好几个电话
I thought you'll with the boss, she find you a couple of times.
哦 是吗
Oh, did he?
我想知道
I wonder why...
兵营非要他回去
He has to go back to the back.
我就去买东西了
I went to go shopping.
嘿 你怎么回事
Hei, what's happened to you?
这 这衣服是谁的
Who... whose dress of that?
我的
It's mine.
是你的
Yes!
我把所有的钱都花了
I spend my last penny.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
是啊 我疯了
Yes, quite, quite.
我买了顶帽子 真漂亮 还有鞋 手提包 手套
I bought a hat, a lovely hat, and shoes, and bag, and lovely... and...
我的结婚礼服
My wedding dress.
哦 玛拉 你的意思是
Oh, Myra... youdon't mean...
是的 我要结婚了
Yes, I am going to be marry.
哦 亲爱的
Oh, darling!
快过来给我一个拥抱
Come here and give me a hug.
哦 真的
Wonderful...
是哪天 哪天
When, when?
明天早晨 在圣马修教堂
Tomorrow morning at St. Matthew's Church.
基蒂 我快乐极了
Oh, Kitty, I'm so madly happy.
哦 亲爱的 我简直不能相信
Oh, darling, I can't believe it!
我也一样
Neither can I.
哦 我要哭了
Oh... I want to cry.
我哭了一整天了
I've been crying all day.
哦 真是难以相信
It's unbelievable!
这种事简直不可能发生
Anything I could do to hang...
太好了
It's so wonderful!
哦 这可跟夫人开了个玩笑
Oh, what joke on Madam.
基蒂 你快来
Kitty, are you coming?
哦 好 马上就来
Yes, all right, wait a second.
我们去剧场 你去吗
You're coming just...You're on your cross.
当然去 我不能拆夫人的台呀
I wouldn't have let Madam done for anything.
那马上来吧
OK. We have to hurry
来吧 快走
Come on.
哦 姑娘们
Oh, Girls!
姑娘们
Girls!
嘿 莉迪娅
Hei! Lydia...
姑娘们
Girls!
你们想得到吗
What do you think?
玛拉要结婚了
Myra's going to be marry?
结婚
Marry?!
玛拉
Myra...
我告诉她们
May I tell them?
你不反对吧
You don't mind, do you?
木已成舟了
You seem to done it!
跟谁
What's his name?
罗伊克劳宁
Roy Cunning.
你是克劳宁夫人了
Oh, Mrs. Cunning, I declare.
我真替你高兴
I'm so happy for you...
玛拉 亲爱的
Oh, you're a darling...
我都快要哭了
I feel like crying too.
我们时间不多啦
But we haven't got enough time.
快走吧 我们要迟到了
Come on, we are late for the theater.
走吧 姑娘们
Come on, girls.
玛拉 你的电话
Miss Myra, you're wanted on telephone.
谢谢
Thank you.
喂
Hello!
是啊
Yes!
哦 不
Oh... no...
什么时候
When?
哦 太可怕了
Oh! That's terrible!
不能让你多留一天吗
Can't they give you one more day?
非得走
You have to...
哦 当然 我马上就来
Of course, I'll come to.
我爱你
I love you.
怎么了
What is it?
怎么回事
What happened?
命令改了
The order has been changed.
他今晚就出发
He's going to Madrid.
火车二十五分钟后就开
The train is leaving within 25 minutes.
哦
Oh...
我要去送他
I am going to see him now.
上哪儿去
Going where?
滑铁卢车站
Waterloo Station.
你不能去
But you can't.
你赶不上回来演出 夫人她
You won't be back in time for the show!
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
玛拉 别去了
Myra, please!
夫人绝不会原谅你的
She'll never forgive you, never.
别去了 玛拉
Don't do it, Myra!
也许再也见不着他了
I may never see him again.
火车要开了
She's just going, sir.
请原谅
Excuseme.
对不起
Sorry.
玛拉
Myra!
罗伊
Roy
玛拉
Myra!
罗伊
Roy!
玛拉
Myra...
玛拉 亲爱的
Myra darling...
他走了吗
Did he leave?
你们谈了吗
Did you talk to him?
到底见到他没有
Did you see him at all?
就看到他一眼
Just called him some.
哦 真倒霉
Oh... what a sham!
我打不到车
I couldn't get a taxi.
他们又说错了站台
They took me to a wrong platform.
哦 他 他会回来的
Oh... he'll be back.
他会平安无事的 玛拉
He'll be all right.
仗不能老打下去呀
The war can't last forever
是的 他会回来的
Yes, he'll be back.
晚上好 玛拉
Good evening, Myra.
承蒙您不弃 您还是回来了
It's very condescending for you to come here at all.
她很伤心 夫人
She's very unhappy, Madam!
她未婚夫被调到前线去了
Her fiancee was called to the front.
我对军队调动不感兴趣
I am not interested in talk moment.
她本来明天就要结婚了
She was to be marry in the morning.
这我也不感兴趣
No any social event.
整个世界并不仅仅只有芭蕾啊
The whole world doesn't begin and end with ballet.
我的世界是的
My world does.
只要你跟我在一起你也一样
And while you are with me, so must yours.
这条规定对玛拉已经不再适用了
The prescription does no longer apply to Myra.
哦 别开除她 夫人
Oh, don't sacrifice her, Madam!
我警告过你
I warned you.
你现在被开除了
You are dismissed.
我认为这不合理
I've never heard such unreasonable...
小心点 基蒂
Be careful, Kitty...
不
No, I won't be careful...
我受够了
I am fed up with her.
这两年里我早就想跟也说了 现在我就要对你说了
I've been warning and telling for two years, now I'm going to tell you...
要是你不爱听的话 你是活该
And if you don't like it, you can love it.
我早就烦透你这种专横了
I'm sick of you and your irritability.
你把我们当成是一群奴隶 还说是什么纪律
You treated us a lot of slaves and chorally discipline.
哼 根本不是
Here and that.
你只是喜欢虐待我们而已
It's just you're enjoying bulling us.
莉迪娅
Lydia.
是 夫人
Yes, madam.
明天十一点钟的排练
Rehearsal tomorrow at 11.
给我补两个后备演员
With "TWO" under studies.
再见
Good night!
哦 和芭蕾分手了
Well, no more ballet to me.
那个母老虎 我可受够了
I am sick of the highbrow and feet.
你我两只丑小鸭
You and I, ducky
得去演歌舞了
Are going to get the interview.
只要找个经理安排进去就行了
Oh, we got to get to do it some engage to put while on.
这事很简单
That will be simple.
基蒂
Kitty?
什么
Yes?
你真认为
Do you think?
有时
Occasionally.
什么
What?
你认为他会给我写信
Do you think you're right?
你好
Hello.
我回来了 那个活儿没弄到手
I am back and I didn't get the job.
基蒂 你吓了我一跳
Kitty, you stop off me.
我
Did I?
对不起
Sorry.
我完了 你怎么样
Well, Myra, I am all settled town, how about you?
不走运
No luck.
没来信
There's nothing there.
你不用找了
No reason for looking.
我上星期刚寄走 我也没想他来信
Well, while I doing last week, I didn't really expect...
服装店怎么样
How about the dress shop?
要熟练工
Fairly needed.
茶馆呢
Fetero?
满了
Filled.
当然了
Naturally.
他们把我列入候补了
They put me onthe waiting.
那只是安慰 是吗
It's confidence, isn'tit?
哦 玛拉 我们俩真是太成功了
Oh! Myra, we're a couple of howling successes,
简直是登峰造极
sitting on the top of world, aren't we?
你的情绪不太好 对吗
You're in nice mood, aren't you?
怪不得一个人坐在暗处伤心呢
No wonder you're sitting here and started feeling sorry for yourself.
不 我不会伤心 永远不会
I don't feel sorry for myself, who will?
问题是你饿着肚子
Probably you didn't eat and you're hungry.
来 帮帮我的忙
Come on, give me a hand.
吃点东西你就不会这样了
You'll feel better when you have something to eat.
玛拉
Myra...
可能你不愿意听这个
You're probably sick of sitting here...
我们为什么不让罗伊知道呢
Honestly, why don't you let Roy know...
说我们没工作
We're out of work?
说我们垮了
That we're broke!
完全垮了
Flat broke!
只剩最后一个罐头了
Down to our last tin!
他会担心的
Only why?
他担心总比我们挨饿好
Better let him worry that we are starving.
哦 我们没有挨饿
Kitty, we're not starving.
也没人挨饿
Nobody is starving.
那是因为没来得及说饿死了
You mean people starveonly to tell about it.
我不知道我们该怎么办
I don't know what are we going to do.
我们在剧团找不到工作 也没别的活可干
Can't get job in the show, can't get anywhere else.
夫人要在我就去找她 顾不得自尊心了
Madam was down here, Igo to her with pride or no pride.
可是现在没人可找了
But it is just no body.
玛拉 我害怕
Myra, I am frightened!
我从来没有害怕过
I have never been frightened before.
我不想这样
I don't like it.
哦 基蒂
Oh, Kitty...
也许我太自私不让罗伊知道
Perhaps it's selfish on me not to let Roy know.
我有那种愚蠢的 自尊心
Perhaps it's sort of stupid pride about it...
基蒂 熬一熬
Can't we wait just a little while?
就再熬一阵吧 情况总会变好的
Just alittle while longer, something must till happen.
要不是这样 我就
If it doesn't...
好
Well...
哦 是梅格太太要房租来了
Oh, its bedge, for therent
我说你去排练了
Pretending you're in rehearsal
好的 好的
Oh, yes!
莱斯特小姐吗
Miss Lester?
我是莱斯特小姐
I am Miss Lester.
给您的 小姐
For you, Miss Lester.
谢谢你
Thank you.
没关系
Quite all right, Miss.
基蒂
Kitty?
花
Flower!
简直不能想象
I can't imagine!
我看看 把它放这儿
Put them down here.
哦 多可爱
Oh, they're lovely!
谁送的
Who do you suppose...
基蒂 是罗伊的笔迹
Kitty, it's Roy, it's handwriting.
十五 十八 二十
Fifteen, eighteen, twenty...
二十 哦 至少花了一英镑
Twenty... oh... it must cost a pound at least.
这足够我们吃一星期的饭了
Oh, enough to buy a lot of food for whole week.
有人回家度假 我托他买了送给你
While my man got leaves, you'll be seeing these through him.
借此表示我深切的
And with them I send you warm...
我们 我们可以把它卖给花店
We could sell them to the florist to the corner buy ourselves real meal.
可是我 我知道你不会赞成的
But I... don't think you favor the idea?
不赞成
No!
哦 基蒂
Oh! Kitty!
他母亲要来了
His mother's coming here.
来伦敦
To London?
是的 你听
Yes, yes, Listen...
我母亲向红十字会请了 两天假
My mother's launching a few days from a Red Cross,
准备进城特意去看你
where is coming to town and expect to see you.
你们会合得来的
I know you are to get well with her.
她人不错
She's very nice.
她跟我一个脾气
In fact, she's quite like me.
哦 基蒂 怎么办呢 不能让她上这儿来
Kitty, do I... I can't have her here!
为什么呢
Why not?
我们开个小宴会 打开最后一个罐头
Let's give her a little party and rob a lot of tin.
还是在别处见她吧
Let's get meeting at somewhere...
喝点茶吧
For tea perhaps.
哦 基蒂 你想 是他妈妈呀
Oh! Kitty, but imagine his mother!
跟他妈妈见面我紧张极了
I'm often not meeting with her either.
爱情弄得你晕头转向了
Why are you funny of dragging them?
她会喜欢我吗
I wonder if she doesn't like me.
哦 应该喜欢
Well, she'd better.
欢 要不我们就不请她了
Or won't we fire him at all!
玛拉 你在发抖
Myra, can't be!
哦 基蒂
Oh, Kitty!
见到她就好像见到罗伊一样
Don't you see the meeting her will be like seeing Roy again!
你一向待我这么亲
Don't be such a darling to him!
也许现在我能报答你了
Now perhaps I can start to repay you.
知道吗
No.
我有种感觉 从现在起一切都会好起来了
I'll see it from now on everything gonna take turns to turn better.
我敢肯定
I am sure I do.
一个人
One?
不 两个人
No, that'll be enough one minute.
有靠窗的桌子吗
Is there any table near by the window?
有的
I think so.
哦 不 谢谢你 我要等一个朋友
No, thank you, I'll wait her... for my friend.
她是克劳宁夫人 我是莱斯特小姐
She is lady Margate Cunning, I am Miss Lester.
她要来了请你带她到这儿来找我
If she come, would you direct her to be here?
好的
Certainly.
请问几点了
What time is it... please?
差十分五点 小姐
It's ten minutes to five, Miss.
谢谢
Thank you.
您的朋友好像耽搁了
Your friend seems been held up.
是的
Yes.
您是不是先来杯茶喝着等她
Surely you would like a cup of tea while you're waiting, Miss.
哦 不 谢谢 她一会儿就要来的
Oh, no, thank you, I am sure she'll behere any minute.
你要看晚报吗
Perhaps you can take look at these evening papers.
哦 谢谢
Oh, thank you.
阵亡军官
克劳宁
好点吗 小姐
Feeling better, Miss?
来 再喝一口
Here, taking another sip.
您晕过去了
You fan, don't you?
您把我们吓坏了
Well, you did give us a fright?
是不是到休息室去躺一会儿
Wouldn't you like to go the rest room lie downa little bit?
不 我 我看我还是呆在这儿吧
But I... I'd rather stay here if you don't mind.
那么您就再喝一口
Let's take another drop of this thing.
好点了
Better?
是吗
Sure?
就会好的
I'll be all right.
坐这儿歇歇吧
Sit quiet and rest.
你朋友要是不来 我们给你叫辆汽车
If your friend doesn'tcome, I will call a taxi.
莱斯特小姐
Are you Miss Lester?
是的
Yes.
我是玛格丽特克劳宁 罗伊的母亲
I am Margaret Cunning, Roy's mother.
我让你久等了
I'm afraid I get you waiting.
真是对不起了
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
火车误了半个钟头
My train was half an hour late.
这年头你也知道
You know how this tidies day's?
不过我是特意从苏格兰赶到这儿 来跟你见面的
But I come straight From Scholand to keep this appointment.
我希望你会原谅我
So I do hope you forgive me.
吃点什么呢
What should we have?
茶
Tea?
点心
Little cakes?
不 不 谢谢 不用了
No... no, thank you.
我一会儿就走
I don't think I can stay any long.
那就来一杯茶 再来几片面包
Tea for one then, and some thin toasts.
我想你不会马上就走吧
I do hope you're not going to run off once.
我一直非常想见见你
I wanted so much to meet you.
可我实在是忙 你知道
But I've been so terribly busy you know,
我正在把一个古老的乡镇 改变成伤兵的疗养所
I've been turning all country place into a rested home for wounded men
哦 对了 我从苏格兰给你打过电话
By the way, I telephone you from Scotland to the hotel where
打到罗伊说的那个旅馆
Roy told me you are staying.
可他们说你已经走了
But they said you got away.
后来我想跟你们剧团打听你
And then I try to get in touch with you through the Ballet.
可听说剧团去美国了
But they said you've got to America.
我正要给罗伊打电报 就收到了你的便条
After about a while ago when your news came.I have my mails disforwarded.
我把信写给他是有原因的
There are reasons.
哦 亲爱的 这个你不用解释了
Oh, my dear, I didn't mean to pride.
请原谅 亲爱的
Forgive me, mydear...
你不是怕我吧
But you're not afraid of me, are you?
我知道跟自己未来的婆婆见面 是有点战战兢兢的
I know it is a little bit of odd, dear, meeting one's future children in law.
我记得我也怕过
I don't remember how I drag it...
可是我并不可怕
But I am not that terrified, am I? .
我相信我们会相处得很好
I know we're going to be good friends?
从罗伊的信里我感到我已经了解你了
I feel that I know you already through Roy's letter.
我要写信告诉他 我们已经见过面了
And I want to write him and tell him
而且我们彼此都有好感
you and I have met and we like each other very much.
我可以这样写吗
May I write him that?
是的 是的 当然
Yes, yes, of course!
我想你一定想了解
I suppose there're a lot of things you want to know
有关罗伊的一些事
about Roy that I could tell you...
我也肯定你会告诉我很多有关他的事
And I am sure that things about him you could tell me.
怎么还不给您送茶
Why aren't they bring your tea?
真是太慢了
They are very slow.
要我去催催吗
Should I call a waitress?
不麻烦了 我并不着急
Don't bother, I'm no hurry.
你是不是不愿意我向你提到罗伊
Would you rather that I didn't speak to you about Roy?
不 不
No, no...
你这是想到哪儿去了
Why should you think that?
我只是没什么话可说
What is that to say?
请原谅 亲爱的 你没有不舒服吧
Forgive me, my dear, but are you quite well?
哦 是的
Yes, yes, of course.
我刚喝了点
I... I had a drink...
喝了点
That's all.
我 我觉得有点
That made me feel... funny.
有点晕
Weird!
苏格兰怎么样
What did I cangot Scotland?
我从来没去过那儿
I had never been there.
居然还有这么一个安宁的地方
Oh, it sounds of quange, you know that? Had that in peace?
爱尔兰也很安宁
Pecans of island?
我也没去过那儿
I've been there neither.
你为什么这么看着我
Why are you stared at me like that?
我尽力用罗伊的眼光看待你
I am trying to see you as Roy sees you.
玛拉 我要你别忘了我是努力想做你的朋友的
Myra, I want you to remember that I try to be your friend.
我来这儿是因为罗伊要我来 而且我也愿意来
I have come because Roy wanted me to come, and because I wish to.
或者我们改日再见吧
Perhaps we'll try again someday.
也许等罗伊下次休假 他会带你来庄园的
Perhaps on Roy's next leave he'll bring you to the country.
再见 玛拉
Bye-bye!
那位夫人走了
The lady is leaving, Miss.
玛拉
Myra!
谁呀
Who is it?
莱斯特小姐出去了吗 克拉克太太
Does Miss Myra Lester gone out? Mrs. Clack?
什么 什么事
What? What isit?
莱斯特小姐上哪儿去了
Where is Miss Lester?
我怎么知道 她出去了
How should I know? She went out.
什么时候
When?
一个小时前
About an hour ago.
你不该让她走
You should've never let her.
她身体不好不能出去 再说又是这么坏的天气
You know she's not well enough to go out. Not like this too.
这种事我管不着 我管不着
This is not nursing house, Miss Melody, not your nursing home.
玛拉 你上哪儿去了
Myra, where have you been?
你有什么事情这种天气还出去
Whatever made you go out at night like this!
你出去还淋了一身雨
You will got the cold in rain too.
赶快上楼去躺一会儿
Now you come on and stay in bed.
几个月啦 我辛辛苦苦的让你养好身体
I spend several months trying to build you up
可你干这种傻事
You're going to do silly thing like this.
我真是管不住你了
I can't trust you out of my sight.
你快去把衣服脱了吧
Now you get those things off.
快点 你快点
Double quick time too.
我给你冲热水袋
I'll pick you up hot water bottle.
基蒂
Kitty...
哦
Yes...
今晚的演出怎么样
How did the show goes tonight?
哦 跟平常一样
Oh, same as usual.
卖座好吗
Was it good house?
还可以
So so.
怎么
Why?
我到剧场去了
I went to the theater.
我想冷不防叫你高兴一下
I thought I surprise you by calling for you.
哦 是
Oh, yeah!
我是不想让你操心
See, Myra, I didn't want to worry you.
现在我不再跳你说过的那种舞了
See, I am in the different order of the show than what I've said...
我在跳一种比较低级的舞
I was in a cheap sort of show, so...
基蒂 你没有工作 一直没有工作
Kitty, we've never got a job at all, we never did have one.
我们怎么过的
How we've been living?
只要活着 管它怎么过呢
What differences make as long as we live!
钱哪儿弄来的 哪儿弄来的
Where's the money coming from?
你以为从哪儿弄来的
Where do you think I've been getting it?
我本来想瞒着你
Try to keep it from you...
可现在你知道了
Well, you know now.
你是为了我
You did it for me.
不 不是
No, I didn't.
我反正得这么做
I'd done it anyhow.
就这样
So I get!
没有工作
No job?
没有人想和你结婚
No boys want to marry you.
只有些寻欢作乐的人 他们怕活着的日子不多了
Only man want to kill off your eye cause they know maybe you are lost.
基蒂 你是为了我买吃的 买药
Kitty, you do it for me to buy me food and medicine.
我真宁愿死了
I sooner die.
不 不 你不会的
No, no, you wouldn't.
你想死 可你不会死
You think you would, but you wouldn't.
我也那么想过
I thought of that.
可是我没那个勇气
But it wasn't brave enough.
我想活下去
I wanted to go on living.
反正我活下来了 你也会活下去的
Heaven knows why, but I didn't, so would you.
我们还年轻
We're young, and it's...
活着有多好啊
It's good to live!
哪怕过这种日子
Even the life that I'm living now...
哦 是啊
God knows
我也不是说活着容易
I'd better call it the easiest way.
但可能是想到死亡就害怕了
I wonder whether thought of death a little afraid.
我算是懂了 不能做个女人
I know one thing... couldn't being a woman.
也许你会觉得
I suppose you think...
我下贱
I am bitch.
哦 基蒂
Oh, Kitty!
小姐
Hello!
今儿晚上天气不怎么样 是吧
There's a wet weather we have this evening, didn't we?
现在雾散了 天好了
Cleared up nicely, after all!
去散散步 好吗
How about a little straw?
运气好吗
How's luck?
不怎么样
No such thing.
基蒂呢
How's Kitty?
和我差不多
Oh, about the same as me.
啊 这年头谁也不会有什么好运气
Oh, now I think there seems no love from no luck.
是啊 好日子快来了
Oh, well better day to come in the sunset
但愿如此
I hope so.
再见
Tour-to-Ioo!
Bye-bye!
你好 玛拉
Hello, Myra!
运气好吗
How was life?
我还没有打算退休呢
Not exactly prepared to retire yet.
瞧 他们回来了
Well, here they come.
再见
See you.
欢迎回国
Welcome home!
谢谢 宝贝儿
Thanks, ducky!
玛拉
Myra!
玛拉 我简直不能相信
I can't believe it.
真的是你
It's you, isn't it.
玛拉 真是你
It's really you.
哦 罗伊
Oh, Roy...
真的是你
It's really you.
玛拉 亲爱的 让我看看你
Oh, darling! Let me look at you.
我没做梦吧
I'm not dreaming, am I?
刚想去找你 你在这儿了
Think of you are waiting for me.
我
I...
哦 真是奇迹
It's... it's a miracle.
哦 罗伊 你活着
Oh, Roy... you're alive.
几个月来 我一直盼着这一天 我以为看不到你了
Oh, at the once I've waited for this moment, 1241 because I think it will never come.
你怎么知道我回来
How do you know I am come,
和我妈妈谈过了
do you telephone my mother?
哦 亲爱的 别伤心了
Oh... darling!
你
Do you have...
你怎样知道的
How do you know?
过去了 都过去了
It's over, darling, it's all over.
我们永远在一起了
We'll get together for always.
哦 罗伊 你活着
Oh, roy, you're alive.
是的 活得挺好
Yes, drive againstly.
哦 小可怜
Mm... poor darling.
来吧 去那儿坐坐
Come on, we'll go sit down.
哦 亲爱的 别哭了
Ho... darling, don't cry...
结局很美满
It's happy ending.
你想我吗
You miss me?
你以为我
Do you think I was...
你知道我是摧不垮的
Didn't you know I was indestructible?
我们订了婚 我怎么能死呢
How can I die when we were engaged?
怎么能破坏婚约
Do you think I will break our engagement?
哦 不 我不是这种人
Ho... you don'tknow me, young woman.
哦 我受过伤
Well, I was wounded...
把什么都丢了
Somehow lost my identification...
说起来话长 改天再告诉你吧
It's get a long story, I'll tell you someday.
在德国的俘虏营呆了大半年 我头部受伤 几乎动不了啦
But anyhow, I was in Germany prison camp, pretty nervously signed off,
可我终于出来到了瑞士
but... I got out at last from Switzerland.
妈妈也到瑞士来照顾我
Mother came over of course.
实习医师了解我的
My intern knows mine.
你和她失去联系了
And I heard that... she lost touch with you.
我都快疯了
I was lost my mind.
怎么回事啊
What happened...
她没找到你
Did she find you?
你和妈妈联系过吗
Did you get contact with her?
没有
No.
你不知道我回来
Then, you didn't know I was coming.
不
No.
那你来车站干什么 在等个朋友
Well, you stood in the station while looking for a friend?
啊 那个朋友就是我了
Well, I am the friend you are looking for.
他是谁
Who was he?
你非得告诉我他是谁
I insist upon knowing.
他是谁
Who was he?
是一个姑娘 不是特意等谁
Oh, just a girl, no one in particular.
你不是特意等谁
Ho... just a little short of American...
而我一下子碰上你
I should run madly into your life
真是奇迹
in this case your wedding for no one particular.
啊 来了
Ah... here we are!
你瞧这茶好浓啊
Good strong tea.
非常提神
This will buck you up
来 喝点
Come on, drink this.
我想和你谈谈
I want to talk to you.
有好多话要问你
A thousand of questions.
靠什么生活
Where have you been up to?
有工作吗
You got a job.
在哪儿
Where is it?
多少薪水
What does it pay?
说实在的 多点少点没关系 你就要不干了
Mm... doesn't really matter, because you're quitting it.
你马上就要不干了
You're quitting it at instant.
这次我决不让你消失在我的视线
I'm not going let you out of my sight this time.
就要和我结婚了 你懂吗
Not when we are marry, you understand that?
哦 你当然受了很多苦
Oh, darling, you have been through a lot, haven't you?
生活很艰难 啊
Pretty tough, Mm?
我又不在你身边
And I wasn't there to help you.
不过 一切都过去了
But that's all over now.
我要弥补过去
I'm going to make up for you.
我要让你过得舒服
I'm going to make things easy for you.
我不愿意看见你流泪 除了为了幸福
I never want to see you cry again except for happiness.
要是我知道你还活着 你还活在人间
I've really had known that you would alive that you would in the world.
我不离开你了 亲爱的
I'll never leave you again, darling.
永远不
Never!
好 莱斯特小姐
And now, Miss Lester...
我有个设想
I have a program.
我是个有设想有行动的人
A man with a program, a man of action.
我打电话告诉妈妈 我找到了你
I am calling my mother that I found you in record of time,
坐晚车回来
And we're coming up in evening train.
抱歉 玛拉
Excuseme, Myra.
我去打电话
I'll find a phone.
你等一会儿 别走开 我就回来
Don't you move until I come back to you.
玛格丽特夫人 我们九点零七分到
The fact is lady Margaret we'll be up there at night at six...
罗伊 有件事我一定要跟你说
Hold on, Roy, I must speak to you...
有件事我一定要跟你说
Something I must speak...
真的
Will you?
这太好了
That'll be marvelous!
谢谢 妈妈 再见
Thanks, Mother, good bye.
啊 就这样
That's all set.
罗伊 你得听我说
Roy, you mustn't!
什么事
What is it?
我不能跟你到乡下去
I can't go to the country with you.
这根本不可能
It's... quite out of the question.
为什么
Why not?
请你别问我 我就是不能去
Please don't ask me, but I... I simply can't.
我非得问你 你非得告诉我
Don't ask, God! You'vegot to tell me.
哦
All right.
我 我太不像样子了
I look terrible for one thing.
我 我连衣服也没有
I haven't have any clothes.
我真的哪儿也不想去
I... I really can't go anywhere.
哈 哈 小傻瓜
Ha... ha, you little fool.
让我看看 你说得过分了
Let me tell you one thing, I think you're exaggerating.
唔 我看也许你说得有点道理
Now when I look at you, I perhaps understand what are your say?
未来的克劳宁太太 怎么样
Well, Madame Cunning to be, we'll see what we can do?
你愿意做伦敦最时髦的女人吗
How would like to be the smartest woman in London?
不 我不能
No, Roy, I can't.
玛拉 亲爱的
Well, darling...
恐怕是我太愚蠢了 又自负又愚蠢
I am afraid I have been stupid, conceived stupid.
因为你一直在我心里
Cause you've never been out of my thought, so I...
哦 我还以为你也跟我一样
I took it for granted that it was the same with you.
你是不是有人了 玛拉
There's someone else, isn't it, Myra?
当然 你以为我死了
After all, you thought I'm... dead!
你已经有人了
There is someone else, isn't it?
别怕 告诉我
Don't be afraid to tell me.
哦 罗伊 当然我没有别人
Roy, of course there isn't anyone else.
也不可能有
There couldn'tbe.
我爱你
I love you
别人我谁也没爱过
I never love anyone else.
今后也不会
I never shall.
这是真话 罗伊
That's the truth, Roy.
我就想知道这个
That's all I want to know.
那好 亲爱的 你笑笑
Oh, darling, smile for a change.
不会笑了吗
Have you forgotten how?
真是个好姑娘
That's a good girl.
我简直不能相信还能见到你
I can't believe I'm with you again.
可你见到了
But you are.
高兴吗
Happy?
高兴
Yes!
我呢 高兴得发狂了
Firstly, I am delirious!
走 买东西去
Come on, we're going to shop.
玛拉
Myra!
这是怎么回事
What's all these?
你从店里偷来的
Have you taken to shop lately?
哦 基蒂 亲爱的
Oh, Kitty darling!
罗伊他活着回来了
Roy's alive, he's back, he's here!
罗伊
Roy?
嗯
Mm!
不
No!
是的
Yes!
他回来了 今天一下午我们都在一起
He's back, we've been together whole afternoon.
他随时都会来这儿的
He'll be here any minute.
基蒂 他想跟我结婚
Kitty, he wants to marry me.
哦 不 这种事是不可能的
Oh, no, that things don't happen.
是真的
It's true
哦 这可太好了
Oh, Kitty, it's going to be so wonderful.
对你也好
For you too.
我做罗伊的妻子 对你再好不过了
No things will be too good for you when I am Roy's wife.
我知道你想什么
Oh, I know what you're thinking.
我也在想这个
I have been thinking too.
你认为我这样太可怕了 是吗
You think that'll be dreadful owl, don't you?
他知道吗
Does he know?
不
No.
你以为这样可以混过去
Do you think you can get away with it?
你是说骗他
You mean deserving him?
对
Yes.
我打算告诉他
Oh, I'm going to tell him.
人可以分为两大类 玛拉
There are two sorts of people, Myra.
一种人生来走运 一种人生来倒霉
Those who get breaks and those who don't!
现在我要走运了
Well, I'm going to take a break.
我不想倒霉下去
Now I am not going to think.
你不是说过你想活下去吗
You remember you once said that you wanted to live?
我也想活下去
Well, I want to live.
这是我活下去的机会
This is my chance for last.
我要跟他走
I won't let him go.
他那么善良 基蒂 那么可爱 纯洁 那么好
He's so kind, Kitty, so sweet, clean, and wonderful.
我会一生忠于他的
I'll devote myself to him.
再说这也是他的幸福 基蒂
After all, his happiness too, Kitty.
他爱我 他一直在等我
He... he loves me, he's waited for me.
就我的灵魂来说 我也在等他
And my soul... I've waited for him.
我能回到他身边吗 说呀 基蒂
Tell me, I cango to him, please.
那就没什么一定之规了
Guess there's no rules, Myra.
要是你觉得好 他也觉得好
For what you feel, what he feels.
基蒂
Kitty!
当然 如果他是真的爱你
After all, he's mad enough about you.
那就总算熬出来了
May make up for everything.
是这样 是这样
Must! Must!
那就试试
Oh, try it.
跟他走
Go to him!
哦 基蒂
Oh, Kitty.
周围有几英亩 玛拉
The ancestor'sstraw aches, Myra.
我各处都领你看看 不嫌烦吧
Shall I point out the things we are proud of no matter how boring.
真漂亮 真是漂亮极了
Oh, it's beautiful, simply beautiful.
妈妈全会领你看的
Mother will take you all over these.
可你别说我带你看了
You must turn right to show you a thing.
要像第一次看到那样
Seeing all of these first time on earth.
也得这么热情
Being enthusiastic too.
这还不容易
That one will be difficult.
在这么个地方度过童年时代 真是太好了
It must be wonderful to spend one's childhood in a place like this.
是啊 那可得年轻
Yeah, it's great when you're young.
的的确确的年轻
When you're really young.
哦 罗伊
Oh! Roy.
你以为自己老了吗
Do youthink yourselfis old?
经过这场战争谁还会年轻呢
No one's spend this war is young.
是这样的 我知道
Now that's true.
记得朗 费罗的诗句吗
You remember long for those line
童年的回忆是无边无际的
their thoughts of you are long long box.
玛拉
Myra!
什么 罗伊
Yes, Roy.
我们在一起真好啊 你说呢
We are overly good to get together, don't you think?
请回答呀 我是说这是一个问题 需要回答 好或者不好
Rips, I mean that was a question requires an answer "YES" or "NO".
好
Yes.
你的回答很正确
Your answer is correct.
我的家 亲爱的
Hello, how are you, darling?
妈妈
Mother!
玛拉 我太高兴了 又见你了 亲爱的
Myra, I am so glad to see you again, my dear.
这有多好啊 罗伊这么快就找到你了
Isn't it wonderful Roy finding you so quickly.
我真相信这是天意
I really believe that providence.
我看是天意
I am sure of that, mother.
谢谢 玛格丽特夫人
You're very kind, lady Margaret.
罗伊 我希望你没带玛拉去转过
Roy, I do hope you haven't show Myra anything.
我要亲自带她四处去看看
I want to show her around myself.
我哪儿都没领她去过
I didn't show her a thing.
很好
Good!
来吧
Come!
我真是太高兴了
Oh, I am so happy, I am...
你好 巴恩斯
Hello! Barns!
哦 罗伊先生 请你原谅
Oh! Mr. Roy, do excuseme.
我一个下午都在等候您的马车 还是错过了
I've been waiting all afternoon, but the dog come, and then I missed it.
你也许会说正是关键时刻
Just at the exclusive moment, he may seed.
哦 巴恩斯
Well, as a matter of fact, Barns...
可是我错过了欢迎委员会 我想使她加深印象
I missmy welcoming committee for their present of Miss Lester.
这是我的未婚妻莱斯特小姐
However, this is my future wife, Barns.
玛拉 这是巴恩斯
Myra, this is Barns.
你好
How do you do!
你好 小姐
他把我从小带大的
Drop me up from baby.
你要想听 他会详细跟你说的
Show you all about the details if you let him.
哦 我很愿意听
Oh, I love to hear wiser.
哦 他给我们添了不少麻烦 莱斯特小姐
Well, he gives awful a lot of troubles, Miss Lester.
他可不算是个乖孩子 不过谁都喜欢他
He wasn't when you called a good child, but he couldn't resistant.
有一次他从树顶上往下跳
One day, he jump off from a tree tall...
那个我跟她说过了 巴恩斯 你来点新的吧
I told her about that, Barns, you pickup something new.
是
Yes.
妈妈 领玛拉看看她的卧室吧
Come, mother, what about showing Myra to her room?
哦 罗伊 我给忘了
Oh! Roy, I forgot.
恐怕我们就要遭到侵犯了
I'm afraid we're going to be invaded!
侵犯
Invaded?
那些邻居 我想尽办法给你免了
The neighbor I did my best to spare you with whole countryside
可是邻居们今天晚上 都要来看你跟你的新娘
is coming tonight to see you and your bride.
可怜的玛拉
Ho... ho... poorMyra!
你要看到一些奇特的人物了
Going to see some wonderful time!
他们俩真相配 是吗
They do look well, don't they?
是的 可爱的姑娘
She's a lovely girl.
可爱极了
Perfectly lovely!
我看这两位年轻人
I suppose there's so least young people
很快会找我 为他们举行婚礼的
will be pairing professionally busy.
大概明天上午吧 罗伊爱得都疯了
Tomorrow morning I expect Roy's madly in love.
忌妒吗
Jealous?
有点
A little.
可你喜欢她
But you like her, don't you?
非常喜欢
Very much!
越看我越喜欢
More every minutes.
她跳得真漂亮 是不是
She dances beautifully, doesn't she?
她本行嘛
Well, that's here job!
克劳宁家的男人全被那些当众脱衣的女人给迷住了
Those Crunningman, they're always attractive by girls who undressed in public.
你怎么不试试 薇拉
Why don't you try that, Lela.
哈 我没那勇气
Ho, I haven't done that.
说不定还没那身段
I am not quite sure I got the figure.
我跟你说 有不少名门望族的漂亮姑娘眼睛
All I can see is that there are plenty of charming girls,
都盯着罗伊
of good family in the county who would jump off to Roy.
我并不是说我的侄女维多利亚
And I don't mean money speak victory.
他能笼得住吗
I wonder if she can arrange.
谁见过他们俩
Never heard of her.
有谁见过她跳舞呢
Is there any one ever seen her dance?
显然罗伊见过 恐怕他喜欢这样
Well, evidently, Roy seen her, and evidently like it.
你注意了 公爵不在场
You know, just the Duke isn't here.
看来公爵不喜欢她
Evidently, the Duke doesn't like it.
幸福吗
Happy?
是的
Yes!
幸福极了
Completely?
是的
Yes!
陶醉了
Ecstatically?
是的
Yes!
不怀疑了
No doubts?
不
No.
不犹豫了
No reservation?
不
No.
不嫌弃了
No dividism.
不
No.
亲爱的 那为什么你眼睛里含着恐惧呢
Darling, every once I seen your eyes, I see fearness.
为什么
Why?
哦 你日子过得很艰难 这我知道
Oh, life's been hard for you, I know that.
你不得不在困苦中挣扎
You did struggle, and privation... and...
可这一切都过去了
That's all over now.
你安全了
You are save now.
不用害怕了
Don't be afraid.
你不用再害怕了
You need me ever again
我爱你
I love you.
罗伊 你真好 你真
Oh, Roy, you're so good, you're so...
哦 亲爱的 这 这一切是真的吧
Oh, darling, it's unreal, isn't it?
是真的
Yes!
会不会突然醒过来 原来是场梦
Shall we wake up suddenly, find it untrue?
罗伊 别说泄气话
Roy, don't be defeated.
啊 在里面跳舞简直就像活受罪
Other like running the gong there, dancing there...
哦 你刚才很出风头
I hope you're in great success, darling.
都被你迷住了
Everyone's enchanted with you.
他们还没见过呢
But they haven't met me yet.
热吗
You're warm?
对 很热
Yes, very.
要喝点冷饮吗
You like a cooling drink?
好 来一杯
Why, Ilove one!
我去拿咱们家酿的甜酒
I'll get you some of Barns' made famous punch.
清凉柔和 酒劲不小
Cool, innocentand deceptive.
你坐这儿 眼珠也别动 我就来
You sit right here, don't move until I back.
我会跟第一个来的卖艺的跑了
I should run off at your first turning minute.
亲爱的
Darling?
去吧
Gone.
我必须要看看那位年青姑娘
Of course, dear, I came to see that young woman.
她在哪儿啊
Where is she?
把她藏到哪儿啦
Where are you hiding her?
这是玛拉
This is Myra.
玛拉 这是我叔叔 你听到了 大嗓门就是他
Myra, this is my uncle, sorts of those fellows you just said.
您好
How do you do!
哦 这就是玛拉 是吗
So this is Myra, is it?
您来了我真高兴
I am very glad you came.
你干嘛把我们隔开来
Why do you kept us apart?
我的麻烦来了
Mm... now my troubles begin.
罗伊 你刚才说要给玛拉弄点甜酒
Roy, you told me you're going to get Myra some punch.
怎么还不去啊
What about it?
我早知道好景不长 亲爱的
I knew it was too good to last.
亲爱的
Mm... darling.
我们坐吧
Come on, let's sit down.
知道吗 你曾经让我担惊受怕了十分钟
Do you know you gave me the terrible most anxious moment in my life?
我
Did I?
什么时候
When?
我坐在车里等着罗伊
When I was waiting in a cab while Roy was in flat
请求你允许他娶我的时候
asking your permission to marry me.
那你是在外头了
You are outside in the cab?
为什么不带你进来
Why didn't he bring you in?
我想他是不敢吧
I don't suppose he dare.
不错 他是个精明的人
Quite right, very true of you.
他要带进来 我绝不会同意
If he had, I've never given him my concerned.
那我要向你求婚了
I should dissolve for you myself.
我也会说好的
Mm... ha... ha... ha, andl'd say"Yes".
亲爱的 你愿意帮个忙吗
My dear, would you do me a favor?
哦 我愿意
I love to.
是不是能赏光跟我跳个舞
Would you do the other dance with me?
哦 当然
Of course.
可我怕罗伊以为我们私奔了
But I'm afraid Roy would've been looped.
哦 也许我们会的
Well, maybe we will.
好的
All right!
走吧
Ha..., come along.
现在我们上场吧
I haven't move for ages.
来 我们狂欢一下
Come on, my dear, just make entrance.
你跳得真好哇
You dance beautifully, my dear.
哪能不好呢
Quite well, indeed!
你也是
So do you.
哦
I... oh... no.
天哪 天哪 天哪
Gently, gently, gently...
这次跳舞达到我事业的顶峰了
Oh, well... that dance is a kind my thos-vigor
我可以退休写我的回忆录了
I can retired now permanently, write my memories.
您真是太好了
You're offering kind.
我将永远感激你
I shall be always grateful to you.
感激 感激 你在说些什么呀
Grateful, grateful, what're you talking about?
您以为我不知道您今天晚上为什么来
Do you think I don't know why you came here tonight?
并且非得当着这么多人跟我跳舞
Made appoint of dancing in front all of the people?
非得 非得 什么非得
Point, point, what point?
您想当众表示您赞成
You wanted to show them you that approve of me.
您知道这样他们也会赞成了
Cause you knew if you approved, they would.
再说 我也喜欢跳
Incidentally, I Charlie will like it.
您真太好了
Oh, Duke... I...
我想让他们喜欢我
I do so like them to like me, I...
我 我要他们喜欢我是为了罗伊
I want to be success because of Roy...
啊 你知道他们是什么人吗
Oh, you know what these people are.
他们都是好心人 善良的人
They're good people, major, kind people.
不过他们都是老派 转不出他们的老眼光
But they're old-fashioned, rather limited of social ideas.
凡事阿弗历大帝认为好的 就都认为好
What good enough for our fridge to grade good enough meat sort of things.
看见这臂章了
You see that emblem?
嗯
Mm...
断茅
Brokenlodge.
我们团的臂章
Our arrangement battleridge.
也是罗伊的
Roy wears one too.
他们以为保持这种传统唯一的办法
Lately, the only way we keep up to the tradition
就是过枯燥的生活 并跟他们的人结婚
is to lead the dull life from many one of themselves.
他们以为舞蹈演员有点太离格了
Do you think of dancers, someone who little of races...,
我说得客气了
Should I say, put it in mind... Mm... ha...
可惜你不能符合他们的标准
Too bad you can't live up to that idea, Myra, isn't it?
这真有意思啊
You may go to fun, wouldn't it?
有意思
Yes, I would.
罗伊对你这个人的直觉
But Roy's instinct tells him what you are.
也是我对你的直觉
My instinct tells me too.
你忠实 善良
You're sound, and good.
你是绝不会辜负这个臂章的
That bad is never going to suffered your head.
对这一点我要不能肯定
If I will have shown that, I wouldn't welcome you as I do now.
玛拉
Myra?
哦 叔叔
Well, thanks a lot.
我认为我已经很大度了 让你和玛拉呆这么久
I think I've been more than generously for you've been so long with Myra
再久就不行了
The longer will be fool, honey.
是 罗伊
Here's her, Roy.
你还是带她走吧 免得她发现我才是更合适的人呢
You'd better take her away before she discovers the facts in the mask.
你听 玛拉
Listen Myra...
我让他们演奏的 你听
I had them played, let's dance.
Excuseus, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢什么 谢什么
For what? For what?
你们好好高兴去吧
Go and enjoy yourself.
你听 亲爱的 不管我们到哪儿
Remember, darling? Thecandlelight club...
这曲子都跟着我们
It's forever go, isn't it?
今天晚上跟到这儿了
And yes, "tonight"!
进来
Coming.
我不打扰你吗
Do I disturb you?
哦 不
Oh, no.
请 玛格丽特夫人
Please come in, lady Margaret.
我轻轻的敲门 万一你睡了就不叫你了
I'm not very gently... so in case you're asleep, I shouldn't wake.
您请坐下
Won't you sit down!
我想你还没睡
I thought you be awake.
我对自己说她快活得睡不着了
I say she's far too happier excited to be asleep.
睡不着有两种情况
Two things keep one up.
不是太快活就是太悲伤
Very happiness and very miserly.
你说是吧
Don't you think so?
是的
Yes.
不说出来憋得慌 我也睡不着
I couldn't go to sleep either without getting something off my chest,
就像美国人说的那样
So to speak you American said.
你真的不累吗
Are you sure you are not too tired?
不 当然不
No, no, of course not.
上次我们在伦敦会面那件事
It's about our last meeting in London.
我心里一直很苦恼
That is preyedin my mind ever since.
你为那件事怨恨我吧 玛拉
Do you bear graduates me for that, Myra?
不 玛格丽特夫人
Oh, no, lady Margaret.
连成见也没有
I came with prejudice.
我上次一看到你 你好像有点特别
When I saw you, you seemed strange to me.
我认为你不配做
I thought you couldn'tbe...
我心目中的罗伊未来的妻子
Well... what I wanted Roy's wife to be.
我做母亲的除了想给自己儿子找个十全十美的人以外
I have no excuse except mother's excuse for
没别的理由
wanting any possible idea for her son.
你能原谅我吗
Can you forgive me?
这有什么要原谅的呢
But I have nothing to forgive.
第二天一回到家就看到了
When I got home the next day,
关于罗伊可怕消息的电报
I found the telegram telling the drafting news about Roy.
等我清醒过来
And when could think again...
突然想到你是早知道了
It suddenly struck me that youhad known all the time,
你当时已经看到了 报上登了他的名字了
that you've just seen his name in paper.
所以说话颠三倒四的
And you hardly knew what you're saying.
说得对吗
Is that truth?
是的
Yes.
哦 可怜的孩子 当时我要是知道
Oh, you poor child if I only know.
我想尽办法找你 可是你不知去向了
I did my very best to find you, but you disappeared.
我想今后我会弥补这一点的
And now I want to make it up to you in the future.
我很高兴你们能喜结连理 玛拉
I am very happy about this marriage, Myra.
我知道我们会相处得很融洽的
And I know we are going to be wonderful friends.
原谅我上次感情用事
Forgive me for being sentimental.
晚安 我的女儿
Good night, my daughter.
玛格丽特夫人
Lady Margaret!
什么 玛拉
Yes, Myra!
我有话要说
I must speak you.
好的 玛拉
Why, of course, Myra.
我不能跟他结婚
I can't marry Roy.
好好坐下 亲爱的 你说吧
Sit down quietly, dear, tell me.
我得走
I must go away.
我根本不该来这儿
I should never come here.
我早知道不可能
I knew it is impossible.
可我一直在骗自己
...But, I kept conceiving myself.
我一定得走
I got to go away... I...
我再也不见他了
I mustn't see him again.
亲爱的 告诉我 究竟为了什么
My dear, why don't you tell me what it is?
我相信我能帮助你
I'm sure I can help you.
哦 没人能帮我
No, no one can help me.
可是亲爱的 到底是什么事 有那么严重吗
But my dear, what can it be that is so terrible?
是不是你有了别人
Has there been someone else?
玛格丽特夫人 您太单纯了
Oh! Lady Margaret... you are nice.
玛拉
Myra?!
是的
Yes!
是的 是的
Yes! Yes!
玛拉
Myra!?
是的 你心里早明白了
Yes, that's all true.
可你不敢相信 这是真的
It's on your mind, but you're telling yourself it can't be true.
是真的
It's true!
玛拉
Myra!
是的
Yes!
你干嘛不早告诉他
Why didn't you tell him?
我没有这勇气
I didn't have the courage.
我能举出许多理由
Or I can give plenty of reasons.
我又饿又穷
I was hungry, I was poor
我 我以为罗伊死了
I... I thought Roy was dead... but...
我能让你理解 可无济于事
I could make you understand... but it would tell...
哦 我不知道怎么说好
I don't know what to say?
可是这件事我跟你一样有过错
But it's my fault as much as yours...
因为我没能理解你 没能照料你
for not having understood, for not having taken care of...
别再对我这么好
Oh! Don't be nice to me!
要是我
If I...
要是我明儿一早就离开
If I leave early in the morning...
要是我再也不见罗伊
If I never seen Roy again...
你能答应永远也不告诉他吗
Would you promise me he'll never know?
这么伤害他我受不了
I couldn't bear hurt him like that.
玛拉
Myra!
哦 我们明天早上再说吧
Oh! Let us wait until morning.
我们再考虑一下
Let's think this over.
您答应吗
Would you promise?
我答应你
I promise.
谢谢
Thank you.
您真太好了
You've been so good.
我多想成为您所希望的 可是
I wish I could've been all you hope... but
玛拉
Myra!
你这个夜游神
What're your little game about?
这么晚干嘛还到处乱逛
Why are you doing crawling around at this hour?
去妈妈那儿了
You've been with mother?
是的
Yes.
她人不错吧
Isn't she wonderful?
是的 很好
Yes, she is.
我知道睡不着 所以到花园走走
Honey, I wouldn't sleep so I've been walking in the garden,
跟星星谈谈我的好运道
confronting my good luck to the stars.
它们高兴吗
Were they pleased?
哦 它们漠不关心
Mm... they seem to different.
老是一闪一闪的 就爱出风头
They wouldn't do glaring, they're little exhibitions.
哦
Oh!
见过这个吗
Have you ever seen this before?
我想见过的
I think so
给你
Here.
可我给你了 是你的了
But I gave it to you, it's yours.
我看搁你那儿要比我这儿安全点
I think it'll be saver with you, just as are we.
刚才丢在花园里 我急疯了 总算找着了
I dropit in the garden moment ago, I was finding it until I found it again.
我看还是放在你身边好 因为
I think you'd better have it from now on, because...
我们现在是一家人了 正如他们所说
now we are both, as they said, one...
我们俩谁收着不都一样
Really doesn't matter which one keeps it, doesn't it?
它给我运气
It brought me luck.
现在也会给你了
Now it will bring you luck
我给你保存 罗伊
I'll keep it for you, Roy.
我累了 亲爱的
I'm tired, darling.
是的 你好像累了
Yes, you look tired.
辛苦一天了
Penestratenous day for you, darling.
晚安 亲爱的
Good night, darling
再会 亲爱的
Good bye, darling.
干嘛再会 一会儿就天亮了
Why good-bye, it's only for a morning...
因为每次跟你分手就像小小的永别
Because every parting from you, is... is like a little eternality.
我也有这种感觉
That's the way I feel too.
再会
Good bye!
再会 多愁善感的人
Good bye! Little sentimentalist!
明天 整天都属于我们的
Tomorrow, all day for ourselves!
是啊 亲爱的
Yes, my love.
我无法以言语来表达
但我们没有未来
我感激你以及你对我的情义
我无法写出--
再见 我的至爱
玛拉
等着我
Wait for me!
玛拉
Myra!
玛拉 我是罗伊
Myra! It's Roy!
玛拉
Myra!
怎么回事 哦 是你呀
What's going on... oh, it's you.
你好 基蒂
Hello, Kitty!
玛拉在哪儿
Where's Myra?
她不在你这儿
She's not with you?
你说什么
What're you talking about?
她昨晚离开苏格兰了
She left Shaft's Garden last night.
没告诉你
Without telling you?
她不在这儿
She's not been here then.
可她前天还跟你在一起的呀
Without your sincere hospitality with you the other day.
能让我进来吗
Look, can I come in?
当然
Of course!
我刚才正在吃饭
I was just about to eat.
坐吧
Sit down.
出什么事了
What happened?
她留了个条 说不能嫁给我
She left a note she couldn't marry me.
是不是你们家里不太同意
Why, is there any trouble With... with your family?
不 不 不
No...
不能想像 简直不能理解
It's incredible, Kitty, I can't understand it at all.
昨晚上我们还在一起 她说很快乐
When last night we were together, she told me she was happy.
她什么时候走的
When did she leave?
坐头班车 买到伦敦的票
At the first train, took a ticket for London.
她已到了几小时
She must arrive hours ago.
可是她没来过这儿
Oh, she's not been here.
哦 她去哪儿了
Where is she?
基蒂
Kitty?
有件事我一直不明白
There's something I've ever understood.
我一回国就感觉到了
I felt in the back my mind ever since I come home,
这事你知道
You know what it is?
告诉我
Tell me!
你得面对现实 罗伊
I thought you'd got face it, Roy.
我猜她不想再和你见面了
I thought she means you'd never see her again.
为什么
Why not?
我不知道 你别问我
I don't know, don't ask me!
基蒂 究竟怎么回事
Kitty, we'll think more realize...
你不说我就报警 我一定要找到她
if you don't tell me, I go to the police. I got to find her
哦 不 别报警
Oh, no no, don't go to the police.
为什么
Why shouldn't I?
别问了 罗伊
Roy, can you take it?
你非要知道不可吗
No matter what you find out about it?
什么意思 我说了你能经受得住
Answer me, can you take it?
不管是什么 我都一样 一定要找到她
No matter what I find out won't make any difference, I got to find her.
好 那么走
Well, come on then.
我们去找她
We'll look for her!
你好 基蒂
Hello, Kitty!
你看到玛拉吗
Have you seen Myra?
没有
No!
肯定没有吗
Are you sure?
上这儿来的人我没有不知道的
Hei, I know seventy bit what's coming near.
更不用说是玛拉
And Myra particularly!
我跟你说她没来 没来
Everyone I tell she ann... she ann...
那好 谢谢
All right, thanks.
干嘛不跟那位先生坐下来吃点什么
Why don't you and your gentleman sit down here put a bite?
你看见玛拉吗
Seen Myra?
没有
No.
我有四天没见到她了
It's about four times when she gone that in the air...
看见她跟她说我在找她 好吗
If yousee her, tell her I'm looking for her, will you?
好的 基蒂
All right, I will be.
嗨 麦克
Hei, Mike?
你好 大姐
How are you, sister?
你看见玛拉吗
Have you seen Myra?
你要找玛拉
Way for Myra.
她常常要到半夜才会来呢
She don't usually come around to about mid-night.
那好 谢谢
All right, thanks.
罗伊 她好像哪儿也没去
Roy, she do seem to be anywhere.
只有一个地方我们还没找过
Does one place we haven't try?
什么地方
Where is that?
滑铁卢车站
Waterloo Station!
去滑铁卢车站
Waterloo Station, driver!
怎样
Well?
哪儿都没有
Not anywhere.
没有 没人看见她
No, nobody seen her.
哦 罗伊 我害怕
Oh, Roy, I am scared
基蒂
Kitty!
我害怕了
I am scared.
她到底去哪儿啦
Tell me where is she?
她实在混不下去了
She... she couldn't go through with it.
她太忠厚了
She was too honest.
她说过你是她活下去的机会
She said it was her chance to live.
活下去的机会
Chance to live?
她说一切都过去了
That she'll never go back...
她再也不干这种
She'll never to be...
不用再说了
You don't need to say!
我懂了
I understand.
那
Then...
那么她在哪儿
Then where is she?
她不见了
She's lost, Kitty.
她躲着我们
She escapist.
我要永远找她
I'll always look for her.
可找不到
But never find her.
是你吗 玛拉
Is that you, Myra?
你好啊
Hello!
你没嫁人吗
Aren't you was marry?
没有
No!
那个基蒂 她跟我说过
That Kitty, she told me,
你跟了个体面人
Said you got off some top.
我早就说了 哪有这种好事
I know it's too good to be true.
是啊
Yes.
哎 别泄气
Oh, well, cheer up.
反正就这么回事
Things can't be worse.
到火车站去吗
Going down to the Station?
好吧
Oh... well...
我到哪儿都没伴
I'll be all for you sometimes.
再见
To-tuo-Ioo...
我爱你
I love you.
别人我谁也没爱过
I never love anyone else.
今后也不会
I never shall.
这是真话 罗伊
It's truth, Roy.
今后也不会
I never shall.